Inventory of the Cook-Luttrell Papers 1848-1890
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
{Special Collections, College of William and Mary}
Cook-Luttrell Papers, 1848-1890.
Special Collections, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 C77
411 items.
Correspondence, business, tax and legal records, primarily 1848-1890, of various members of the Cook and Luttrell Families of Culpeper and Rappahannock Counties, Virginia.
Cook family,; Luttrell family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence, business, tax and legal records, primarily 1848-1890, of various members of the Cook and Luttrell Families of Culpeper and Rappahannock Counties, Virginia.
The Cook family correspondence is concentrated between 1855 and 1858 and discusses the migration of several members of the family to western Virginia and Missouri, courtship and marriage, farming, and detailed accounts of family visits. The Luttrell correspondence, 1874-1890, contains letters to Mollie Luttrell from girl friends, discussing social events and friends.
The Cook family business and tax records, (1936-1859)-1875, are primarily receipts for accounts with Culpeper County merchants, with those of Thomas Jimson Cook including advertisements and attendance records for a grammar school he taught in his home. The Luttrell business records are primarily the receipts of James W. Luttrell (1813-1884) with Culpeper and Rappahannock County merchants, and included receipts for tuition paid to educate his daughter, [Mollie?] and correspondence concerning his investments in Austin, [Texas?]. Also, assorted business and tax records of the Bywaters family, and a legal document appointing James W. Luttrell surveyor of roads for Culpeper County.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The papers are divided first by type of record and then by family.
Organization
The papers are organized into five Series so that Series 1 is Personal Correspondence, Series 2 is Business Papers, Series 3 is Tax Receipts, Series 4 is Legal Documents and Series 5 is Miscellaneous Papers. Within each series is a Subseries relating to either the Cook Family or Luttrell Family.
Index Terms
Family Names
Cook Family.; Luttrell Family.; Bywaters Family.
Subjects
Women-- Education.; Marriage--Virginia.; Marriage--Missouri.; Courtship-- Virginia.; Agriculture--United States--History--19th century.; Missouri--History--19th century.
Contents List
  Series 1: Personal Correspondence
- Personal Correspondence.
  - Cook Family Correspondence.
    - Alfred Cook Correspondence, 1849-1856. (Box-folder 1:1)
      - Welf[o]rd Johnson, Monticello, Lewis County, Missouri, to "Uncle" Alfred Cook, n.p., 12 Aug[ust] 1849., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
        Concerns lawsuit between Cook and "Aunt" Cecy [Cook?]; mentions contention over estate of "Grandfather" Cook; discusses health of family and occurrence of cholera; progress of wheat, oat, and corn crops; mentions wife Elizabeth.
      - Alfred M. Cook, Pleasant Retreat, [?], to "cousin" [?], n.p., 15 Nov[ember] 1856., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
        Sends news of the family at home; asks after other family members.
    - Burrell Henry Cook Correspondence, 1855-1858. (Box-folder 1:2)
      - Burrell H[enry] Cook, "Mountainview," [Culpeper County, Virginia,] to Kate [?], n.p., 24 March 1855., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
        Reflects on the meaning and necessity of marriage; sends her his love.
      - Helen Mary Gawthrop, Bridgeport, Harrison County, [Virginia] [now West Virginia], to "cousin" Burrell H. Cook, Amissville, Rappahannock [County, Virginia], 18 May 1855., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
        Talks of family and friends; mentions upcoming trip to Kentucky; hopes he is not a "Know-Nothing" as she would disapprove.
      - Helen M[ary] Gawthrop, Bridgeport, Harrison [County, Virginia now West Virginia], to "cousin B[urrell] H. C[ook], Oak Shade, Virginia, 5 August [18]55., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
        Discusses family news, weather, and crop conditions; mentions possibility of going with him to a camp meeting in Kentucky; hopes he will come for a visit this summer.
      - Burrel[l] H. Cook, Boothes Creek, Taylor County, Virginia [now West Virginia] to his brother [Thomas J. Cook], n.p., 29 June 1856., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
        Discusses corn crop; asks him to come to Taylor County; says he can teach school if he wants; including postscript noting death of "Col." Perry and "Uncle" William Corbin; mentions [wife?] Helen Ma[r]y.
      - B[urrell] H. Cook, n.p., to his mother, Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia, 18 Apr[il] 1858., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
        Asks her to sign a financial note and give it to James W. Luttrell for safe-keeping.
      - Burrell H. Cook, Taylor County, Virginia [now West Virginia] to "mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 22 Jun[e] 1858., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
        Discusses weather and corn crop progress; mentions sister Sarah [Susan], and brother, Thomas; asks for $150 to buy a farm.
      - B[urrell] H. C[ook], n.p. to Thomas Jimson Cook, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Thomas Jimson Cook Correspondence, 1846-1858. (Box-folder 1:3)
      - [Y.] L. Settle, [Hampton, Virginia?], to "Tom" [Thomas J. Cook], n.p., [11 Feb. 18]46., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Describes teaching position.
      - Thomas J. Cook and W[illiam] A. Cook, n.p. to "dear friend"[?], 23 Feb[ruary] 1850., 3 pages. ALsS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Protests William's treatment by the [Motsey] Division of the Sons of [Temperance?], and the slander of his name.
      - Thomas J. Cook, [Culpeper County, Virginia], to Burrel[l] Henry Cook, San Jose, Santa Clara County, California, 19 Febuary [February] 1853., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Is glad he has arrived safely and has good prospects; tells news of the family; is anxious to hear his newly-learned Spanish.
      - James W. Corbin, Anderson County, Kentucky, to "cousin" [Thomas J. Cook; Culpeper County, Virginia], 29 July 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Describes his journey home to find his youngest child dead of scarlet fever; has been sick for the past week; wants him to check a land title with the Cumberland County Clerk; includes a list of marriages in the Corbin family.
      - L.A. Corbin, Brandy [Station, Culpeper County, Virginia] to "Tom" [Thomas J. Cook?], n.p., 7 Mar[ch] 1857., ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Asks for repayment of a loan; describes trip to Washington, [D.C., for Presidential inauguration?]
      - Tho[ma]s Cook and Sallie S. [Sarah Susan] Cook, [Taylor County, Virginia][West Virginia], to "mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 16 Jan[uary] 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Discusses trip to the "western lands" to visit brother, Burrell H. Cook; tells of relatives met.
      - Thomas J. Cook and "Sudie," Sarah Susan Cook, [Missouri?], to "Mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 19 Apr[il] 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Describes trip from Virginia to Missouri, and friends encountered along the way; mentions intention to marry in the near future.
      - Thomas J. Cook, Saline County, Missouri, to "nephew"[?], 22 June 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Discusses weather, and crops in Missouri as compared to Virginia; sends love to family members; intends to visit home when possible.
      - Thomas J. Cook, Saline County, Missouri, to "Mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County], Virginia, 3 Nov[ember] 1858., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Discusses bad weather and illness in vicinity; mentions sisters, Sarah Susan, visit and brother, Burrel[l]; also Frank Robinson and family; intends to return home when possible.
      - L.A. C[orbin], Oak Shade, Leurs County, Missouri, to "cousin" [Thomas J. Cook?], [Culpeper County, Virginia?], 24 March [ante 1860]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
        Describes trip from Platte, Missouri to Oak Shade; weather makes travel bad, but is generally pleased with country; was glad to hear family is well; tells of acquaintances and friends living in Missouri.
    - William A. Cook Correspondence, 15 May 1849., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      William Williams, Bridgewater [Rockingham County, Virginia ?], to William A. Cook, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia. Discusses his [WW] budding medical practice; ask Cook to remember him to all his old friends, as he will probably never see them again; mentions his intention to find a wife.
    - Sarah Susan (Cook) Kendrick Correspondence, 1855-1857. (Box-folder 1:5)
      - S.E.G. [?], Culpeper County, [Virginia], to "Sudie" [Sarah Susan Cook]. n.p., 28 November [18]65., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
        Discusses clothing Sarah Susan has asked to have made; mentions acquaintances.
      - Mary M. Benson, [Melvalle?], to "Sudo" [Sarah Susan Cook], Culpeper County, Virginia, 31 Jan[uary] 1857., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
        Discusses arrangements for Sarah Susan to make a bonnet for "M's" trip to Washington in March.
      - "Sallie," Sarah Susan Cook, and Lucy E. [Cook] Marshall, Glenn Mills, [Missouri?] to "mother" [Susan M. Cook] Marshall, Glenn Mills, [Missouri?], to "mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 8 September n.y., 4 pages. (Box-folder 1:5)
        Describes Sarah Susan's conversion experience at a recent revival meeting; has recently been sick, as have many family members; mentions brother, Thomas, and brother-in-law, Joseph Marshall, as well as children, Fannie and "Lilly" [Lila].
      - "Sallie," Sarah Susan Cook, Boone County, [Kentucky], to "mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 16 December n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
        Talks of arrangements for her return to Virginia; mentions brothers, Burrell and Thomas; has been ill and there is a great deal of sickness in the air.
    - Lucy E.(Cook) Marshall Correspondence, 1854-1858. (Box-folder 1:6)
      - Lucy E. [(Cook)] Marshall, [Saline County, Missouri] to "mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 29 Nov[ember] 1857., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
        Describes new home and work associated with taking in boarders; announces birth of a daughter; sends love to family.
      - Lucy E. [(Cook)] Marshall, [Saline County, Missouri] to "mother" [Susan M. Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia], 18 Nov[ember] 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
        Mentions husband [Joseph Marshall] and children [Fannie and Lila]; details her work and her husband's investments in hogs, and his building of a distillery; tells of food she has prepared for the winter; sends her love to the rest of the family.
    - Miscellaneous Cook Family Correspondence, 27 Apr[i]l [18]52. (Box-folder 1:7)
      - [?],Cassville, [?], to Lucie [?], n.p., 27 Apr[i]l [18]52., 2 pages. L. Incomplete. (Box-folder 1:7)
        [Portion of a marriage proposal?]
      - Colonel [Pierce?] Perry and wife, "Mountainview," [Culpeper County, Virginia?], to the Cook family, [Culpeper County, Virginia], 15 Jan[uary] 1854., 1 page. N. (Box-folder 1:7)
        Invitation.
      - [?], Kentucky, to his cousin, Susan [Cook?], Virginia, 30 Apr[il] 1859., 4 pages. L. (Box-folder 1:7)
        Mentions his cousin's ill health; refers to his standing proposal of marriage; discusses one of his two daughters, Becky, and his sons.
  - Luttrell Family Correspondence
    - H. A. Hemper, n.p. to "Francis," Cecy F. Luttrell, n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:8)
      Instructions for dyeing cloth.
    - Mollie M. Luttrell Correspondence, 1874-1880. (Box-folder 1:9)
      - "Cousin," J.G. Luttrell, Linwood, [Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 31 Oct[ober] 1874., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Describes his progress in school; discusses "cousin" Sudie's [Sarah Susan (Cook) Kendrick] new baby, Mary Frances.
      - Annie [Cook] and Sallie [Cook], Meadow View [Washington County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 10 October 1875., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses family news; mentions Sallie's weaving; asks Mollie to visit.
      - L[u]lie R. Spilman, Amissville, [Rappahannock County], Virginia, to Mollie Luttrell, [Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 9 March 1877., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses family news; mentions the marriage of Charlie Rollins; asks after Willie [Mary William Doyle?]; wishes she could join her and Willie at school.
      - [Tola?], Locust Grove, [Orange County, Virginia?], to [Mollie Luttrell], n.p., 26 April 1877., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses making of new clothes; wants her to visit.
      - "Cousin," Tola [?], Locust Grove, [Orange County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 7 June 1877., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses family members; mentions recent trip to Warrenton, Virginia.
      - Annie [Cook] and Sallie [Cook], Meadow View, [Washington County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell], Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 18 [?] November 1877., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Sorry to hear "cousin" Jim [Luttrell] is sick; invites her to visit.
      - "Cousin," Tola [?], Locust Grove, [Orange County, Virginia?], to Mollie Luttrell, [Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 25 December 1877., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Tells her to be sure to visit in the afternoon.
      - John A. Walters, n.p. to Mollie Luttrell, n.p., 10 January 1878., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Invitation to a surprise party.
      - Annie [T.] Cook, Meadow View, [Washington County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], [?] April 1878., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Describes her new dress; asks Mollie to visit soon; mentions Willie Silvey, Fannie [?], and family members.
      - Lulie R. Spilman, Amissville, Virginia, to "cousin," Mollie Luttrell, n.p., 2 June 1878., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Is happy to have received her letter; mentions decline of the Singing School and rise of Temperance Society; asks her to visit soon.
      - L[ulie R. Spilman], Amissville, Virginia, to Mollie [Luttrell], n.p., 29 October 1878., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses friends; wishes she would visit; will visit her soon.
      - Lulie [R. Spilman], Amissville, Virginia, to Mollie Luttrell, n.p., 5 December 1878., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses plans for her [M.L.] Christmas visit; sends love to members of Mollie's family; mentions taffy pull at Mrs. [S.?] Corbin's.
      - Lulie [R.] Spilman, "School Room," [Amissville, Virginia], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia], 1 May 1879., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Has not heard from her old friend; sends much love; mentions Willie Doyle, Annie [?], Martin Pickels, Mrs. Corbin; Lulie's brother is in Baltimore, while Lulie Davis is in Maryland.
      - Willie" [Mary William Doyle], [Green Valley, Bath County, Virginia?], to "cousin," Mollie Luttrell, [Amissville, Virginia?], 18 November 1879., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Discusses new clothes and missing patterns; mentions "cousin" Tabitha's [?] expected visit; hopes Mollie will visit soon.
      - "Willie" [Mary William] Doyle, Green Valley, [Bath County, Virginia?], to "cousin," Mollie Luttrell, Amissville, [Virginia?], 1[0] December 1879., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Has been killing hogs all day and is tired; congratulates her on her new "beau"; mentions a past protracted meeting; had fun at "cousin" S. Corbin's; invites her to visit.
      - Rosa [?], "Laurel Hill School," [Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell], n.p., 9, 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
        Mentions rumor that Willie Silvey is Mollie's new beau, but is sure it cannot be true; attended Dr. Brown's funeral; asks her to visit soon.
    - Mollie M. Luttrell Correspondence, 1881-1890. (Box-folder 1:10-11)
      - Ginnie [?], Hope Mills, Page County, Virginia, to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia], 18 July 1881., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Discusses the heat; is sewing several new dresses; has a new beau but misses the boys in Amissville; saw Bernard [?] and Fannie Anderson at church together; there will be a reunion of Union and Confederate soldiers at Luray [Page County, Virginia].
      - Mollie M. Luttrell, n.p., to Willie [Doyle?], n.p., 13 February 1882., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Asks her to visit or write; mentions friends, Laura and Tola, and "sister" Sudie [Sarah Susan Cook?]; promises to try to visit as soon as the weather clears.
      - "Cousin" Annie Cook, Mead View [Washington County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Rappahannock County, Virginia], 16 October 1884., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Sends condolences at the death of "cousin" Jim [Luttrell?]; mentions intended trip to Baltimore in December.
      - A[?] M[?], Willow Brook, [Louisa County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia], 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Enjoyed recent visit but is now sick; hopes her [M.L.] wedding goes well; send best wishes for Christmas, and mentions local Baptist church's Christmas tree and tableaux; refers to Will [Mollie's brother?].
      - Lucy [O.?] Silvey, Amissville, Virginia, to Mollie Luttrell, [Amissville, Virginia?], 31 August 1889., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Discusses problems with renting a carriage for the drive to the [Baptist?] Association meeting; mentions seeing Willie at Oak Shade, [Virginia].
      - A.T. Luttr[ell], n.p., to Mollie [Luttrell], n.p., 25 March 1890., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Was shocked to hear of Geo[rge] Sheag's death; tells that "cousin" Al Baker has bought a farm near Mollie's home; mentions Willie Jeffries, who will soon be married, and Clarence Pierce; his employer has offered him a house and livestock; talks of potential for profits to be made.
      - Annie [M.], Willow Brook, [Louisa County, Virginia?], to Mollie [Luttrell], n.p., 6 July 1890., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:10)
        Discusses family news; hopes Mollie can join her at a "Bush" meeting.
      - Annie [Cook] and Sallie [Cook], [Meadow Grove, Washington County, Virginia], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Wishes she would visit for "first" Sunday and accompany them to Carter's Run.
      - "Willie" [Mary William Doyle], "School Room," [Amissville, Virginia?], to Mollie Luttrell, n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Mentions "Uncle" Frank [Cook?], his wife [Sallie?] and daughter [Annie?], who have been sick; has had a lot of company lately; wishes she [M.L.] could visit with news of friends.
      - Mary [William] D[oyle], n.p., to Mollie Luttrell, Amissville, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Expects to meet her and "Tola" the following evening for a trip to visit "Uncle" Frank [Cook?].
      - Mary [William] Doyle, n.p., to Mollie Luttrell, [Amissville, Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Wants to know if she is going to "cousin" Tommy's [?], and if "cousin" Hannah Bettie can accompany Mary.
      - "Willie," [Mary William Doyle], n.p., to Mollie Luttrell, Amissville, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Invitation to visit.
      - Bettie E. Grant, Warrenton, [Fauquier County, Virginia], to Mollie [Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia], 21 November n.y., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Sends her trimming and buttons as requested; wishes she would visit soon; mentions mutual friends.
      - Lucy [E. (Cook) Marshall?], n.p., to "Molly" [Luttrell], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Sends her yard goods and a pattern, mentions plans to travel to Fauquier [County?], but will miss going to Battle Run.
      - Lucy Silvey, [Amissville, Virginia], to "Molly" [Luttrell] and Tola [?], [Amissville, Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Can't accept the invitation to visit, but expects to see them the following evening at the "lodge."
      - H. [N.?] Spilman, n.p., to "Miss" Mollie [Luttrell], n.p., n.d., 1 page. ANS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Refers to hat she [M.L.] would like to purchase.
      - [L]ulie Spilman, n.p., to Mollie [Luttrell], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Wishes she were present to share in social gathering; mentions names of friends and family members.
      - Lulie [R. Spilman, Amissville, Virginia], to [Mollie Luttrell], "Chestnut Hill," [Amissville, Virginia?], n.d., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        Wants her to visit soon.
      - Lulie [R.] S[pilman, Amissville, Virginia], to Mollie M. Luttrell, [Amissville, Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:11)
        She [M.L.] is to accompany her [L.R.S.] to church next Sunday night.
  Series 2: Business Papers
- Business Papers.
  - Cook Family: Business Accounts (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Alfred Cook, [Culpeper County, Virginia], 1 October 1836 - 29 January 1846., 24 items. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Financial receipts and notes; merchants include Murray Forbes, William R. Robson, and Crigler and Eggborn.
    - Burrell H. Cook, Amissville, Virginia, [and Taylor County, Virginia], 1 September 1848 - 20 August 1858., 8 items. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Financial receipts for food and dry goods, and account for "boarding the delegates horses," 31 August 1853.
    - Elias Cook and Alfred Cook [Culpeper County, Virginia], 15 September 1845., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Account with John Cooke for goods and services, settled by Thomas J. Cook.
    - Susan M. Cook, [Culpeper County, Virginia], 26 August 1848 - 17 August 1859., 3 items. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Financial receipts for food and dry goods purchased.
    - Thomas J[amison] Cook, Amissville, [Virginia], 1 July 1837 - 17 September 1859., 54 items. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Financial receipts for food, lumber, dry goods; also, advertisements and attendance records for school taught by Thomas Cook; includes notice for lost cow.
    - William A. Cook, Amissville, [Virginia]: Financial receipts, 20 January 1837 - 27 March 1850., 4 items. (Box-folder 2:6)
      Includes promissory note cosigned by Thomas J. Cook.
    - Sarah S[usan] (Cook) Kendrick, Amissville and Oak Shade, Virginia financial receipts, 1 March 1854 - September 1859., 2 pages. (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Lucy E. (Cook) Marshall, [Virginia]. Financial receipt, 26 October 1853., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Miscellaneous Cook family accounts for food and dry goods, 24 October 1843 - 24 September 1873., 5 items. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Luttrell Family: Business Papers.
    - James W. Luttrell Receipts, 1833-1885. (Box-folder 2:10)
      - James W. Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia, 1833-1860., 21 items. (Box-folder 2:10)
        Financial receipts for food, dry goods and services purchased.
      - James W. Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia, 1861-1870., 22 items. (Box-folder 2:11)
        Financial receipts for food, dry goods and services purchased, including tuition paid for schooling of daughter [Mollie?].
      - James W. Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia, 1871-1880., 47 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:12)
        Financial receipts for food, dry goods and services purchased, including letter referring to Luttrell's interests in Texas[?].
      - James W. Luttrell, Amissville, Virginia, 1881-1885., 22 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:13)
  Series 3: Tax Receipts
- Tax Receipts. (Box-folder 2:14-17)
  - Cook Family Tax Receipts, 1858-1882. (Folder 14-16)
    - Cecy Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia: County tax receipts, 1867-1882., 6 items. (Box-folder 2:14)